# MUKHAMMAD NURUDDIN ISMAIL

085231634078 | nurudin 2@live.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nrdnisml/ | https://github.com/nrdnisml

Kec. Kademangan Kota Probolinggo

Freshgraduate informatics student from Politeknik Negeri Malang and completed thesis exam about computer network research on July 22nd 2022. Interested and experienced in computer network and web development by completing several certifications and professional projects in related fields.

### Work Experiences

### Melati Network - Probolinggo

May 2018 - Present

Owner

Social contribution to apply and develop skills in the computer networks and hope that it can be useful for the surrounding community.

 Design, install, configure, and maintain Mikrotik-based intranet and internet connections via wired and wireless transmission in Dusun Melati, Probolinggo.

#### PT Fokus Jasa Mitra - Kec. Kebomas, Kabupaten Gresik

Apr 2022 - Present

Web Developer (Contract, Project Based)

PT Fokus Jasa Mitra is a subsidiary of PT Petrokimia Gresik who engaged in the provision of professional labor services.

• Redevelop Web Application SIMATA to present, organize, manage data, and add some modules based on business processes in the TA-1, TA-2, and TA-3 units of PT Petrokimia Gresik

# PT Petrokimia Gresik - Kec. Kebomas, Kabupaten Gresik

Oct 2021 - Mar 2022

Internship

PT Petrokimia Gresik is a state owned company engaged in the manufacturing industry that produces various kinds of fertilizers and chemicals for agro-industrial solutions.

- · Build Web Application SIMATA-3 (Sistem Informasi Manajemen Turn Around-3) to simplify business processes in the TA-3 unit.
- Make a bill of materials (BOM) for Aluminium Flouride 3 (ALF3) and Zvavelvuure Ammonium 2 (ZA2) Plant as the basis for making a stock holding policy using SAP ERP software.
- · Design, install, and troubleshoot computer network in Rendal Material unit.

# Elecomp Indonesia - Sawojajar, Kota Malang

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

Internship

Software House

• Redevelop web application dental clinic management information system

## Dinas Koperasi, Usaha Mikro, Perdagangan, dan Perindustrian Kota Probolinggo (DKUPP) - Kec. Mayangan, Kota Probolinggo

Dec 2020 - Jan 2021

Web Developer (Freelance)

Government agency that manages the fields of small and medium enterprises, trade and industry.

 Rebuild web and Android applications (WebView) UKM Pintar of DKUPP Kota Probolinggo. Already used by more than 4900 Small and Medium Enterprise (SME) in Probolinggo city.

### **Education Level**

#### Politeknik Negeri Malang - Kota Malang

May 2018 - Jul 2022

Bachelor Degree in Informatics Engineering, 3.80/4.00

SMK Negeri 2 - Kota Probolinggo

Jun 2015 - May 2018

Vocational High School in Computer Network Engineering, 3.10/4.00

### Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Publication (2022): Compiling a textbook with the title "Virtualisasi cloud computing menggunakan proxmox VE" ISBN:
- 978-623-5711-32-4
- Certification (2021): BNSP Web Development Competency
- Certification (2019): BNSP Computer Network Competency
- Certification (2018): MTCNA (MikroTik Certified Network Associate)
- Achievements (2017): First Runner Up of the "Lomba Kompetensi Siswa IT Networking Support" at the probolinggo city level
- Hard Skills: Manage and configure MikroTik RouterOS (Static and Dinamyc Routing, VLAN, QoS, Firewall, Hotspot, Automation)
- Hard Skills: Configure Cisco Router (Basic configurations, static and dinamyc routing in an AS and different AS)
- Hard Skills: Manage and configure Linux Server Debian Based (Sysadmin)
- Hard Skills: Web Development